<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<thread id="2137873" numarticles="3" link="https://boardgamegeek.com/thread/2137873" termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse">
  <subject>Double bluff nearly worked if it wasn't for the pesky pirate</subject>
  <articles>
    <article id="31070071" username="Totality" link="https://boardgamegeek.com/thread/2137873/article/31070071#31070071" postdate="2019-01-24T12:45:21-06:00" editdate="2019-01-24T12:45:21-06:00" numedits="0">
      <subject>Double bluff nearly worked if it wasn't for the pesky pirate</subject>
      <body>Had a reasonable first session, but it wasn't a slam dunk.
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;I as long John hid the treasure in one of the town's near the middle. Clue wise, I used the North South divide to cut off 20% straight off, and then used the 8 mile circle clue in the middle with a bluff token, even though it was true I then followed it up with a six mile clue nearly in the middle again with another fake bluff, however none of the pirates were verifying the clues. After a few tense moments where they nearly found the treasure, they did verify the clues and discovered both were bluffs, directing then straight a way to the column of board outside the two circles.  I'd sold nearly all on the bluff, but then one pirate knew it wasn't in that region and kept on telling everyone that it definitely wasn't there, effectively guiding the active player to the treasure, which they then found. 
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;In hindsight, I should have emphasized completely that this is not a cooperative game and the pirates are not supposed to help each other..... This is hard to do in a learning game where people are trying to help each other with the rules and avoid silly moves.
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Component wise it was very tactile, I couldn't find someway of orientatating the district tiles apart from pattern recognition, wish they had an identifying up mark.  Also, when I was trying to measure for the circle clues I ended up doing it on the mini map avoid giving too much away but it ended up being imprecise.</body>
    </article>
    <article id="31083392" username="flaquito" link="https://boardgamegeek.com/thread/2137873/article/31083392#31083392" postdate="2019-01-25T21:24:09-06:00" editdate="2019-01-25T21:24:09-06:00" numedits="0">
      <subject>Re: Double bluff nearly worked if it wasn't for the pesky pirate</subject>
      <body>The district tiles all have a skull in the marked-out district that is right-side up when North is up, so that should help.
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;And remember that you can always ask the pirates to close their eyes or turn away so that you can measure or check something on the main board.
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;I also played one game as LJS where I told the truth for both of my bluff tokens. It didn't work out very well for me, either. I suspect that there are times when that would be really useful, but I think in that game I would have been better served by actually lying about at least one clue. It's so hard to know.</body>
    </article>
    <article id="31083902" username="Marco P" link="https://boardgamegeek.com/thread/2137873/article/31083902#31083902" postdate="2019-01-26T00:25:41-06:00" editdate="2019-01-26T00:25:41-06:00" numedits="0">
      <subject>Re: Double bluff nearly worked if it wasn't for the pesky pirate</subject>
      <body>&lt;font color=#2121A4&gt;&lt;div class='quote'&gt;&lt;div class='quotetitle'&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;flaquito wrote:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='quotebody'&gt;&lt;i&gt;The district tiles all have a skull in the marked-out district that is right-side up when North is up, so that should help.
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;And remember that you can always ask the pirates to close their eyes or turn away so that you can measure or check something on the main board.
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;I also played one game as LJS where I told the truth for both of my bluff tokens. It didn't work out very well for me, either. I suspect that there are times when that would be really useful, but I think in that game I would have been better served by actually lying about at least one clue. It's so hard to know.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Thanks for posting ! Agreed.
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;As a complement, you can check this:
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a target='_blank' href="https://boardgamegeek.com/thread/2118471/strategic-guide-treasure-island" rel="nofollow noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://boardgamegeek.com/thread/2118471/strategic-guide-tre...&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;Marc</body>
    </article>
  </articles>
</thread>
